<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>彭博太空商业</title>
    <link>urn:kill-the-newsletter:88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0</link>
    <description></description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 15:13:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>为您推荐：今日头条</title>
      <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/jtttxzqatjruei9qsqrv.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/jtttxzqatjruei9qsqrv.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 15:00:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>太空事业：欧洲独立</title>
      <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/4lty0bugijd2b89pshab.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/4lty0bugijd2b89pshab.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 15:10:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>这是全年节省 50% 的季节。</title>
      <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/96eomjoj8ud6zzonvb4q.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/96eomjoj8ud6zzonvb4q.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:01:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>您的访问权限已过期。</title>
      <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/427fitaexfahdljr6881.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/427fitaexfahdljr6881.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:00:34 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>太空业务：关于阿尔特弥斯的最新问题</title>
      <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/ef5mr9mf58iimu7zt653.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/ef5mr9mf58iimu7zt653.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 15:35:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>太空业务：特朗普的冲击</title>
      <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/6agkh880yimx73t1w9z1.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/6agkh880yimx73t1w9z1.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 15:03:36 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>网络降价：立减 170 美元</title>
      <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/2vuzsqjesrgir8fluo1u.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/2vuzsqjesrgir8fluo1u.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 15:00:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>网络优惠：立减 160 美元</title>
      <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/sax5ut5p7rnegka1kspt.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/sax5ut5p7rnegka1kspt.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 15:00:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>太空事业：蓝色之年</title>
      <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/warwg1i8c3bw19569pjn.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/warwg1i8c3bw19569pjn.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 15:01:43 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>这是我们今年的最佳优惠。立减 160 美元。</title>
      <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/b0gzacj2if7hq7zk62mf.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/b0gzacj2if7hq7zk62mf.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 15:00:09 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>抢先体验网络特惠：立减 160 美元</title>
      <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/x6zpg6rhajexml0k1sor.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/x6zpg6rhajexml0k1sor.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:01:48 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>您的访问权限即将到期</title>
      <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/yly1wuzasptaecgw38zy.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/yly1wuzasptaecgw38zy.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 21:30:09 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    </channel>
</rss><?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
 <rss version="2.0">
 <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>urn:kill-the-newsletter:88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0</link>
    <description></description>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 07:06:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
        <title>For you: Today’s top stories</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/jtttxzqatjruei9qsqrv.html</link>
        <description>

              Context changes everything.                  View in browser Please do not reply to this message; it was sent from an unmonitored email address. If you received this message in error, please contact us. Contact Us | Advertise | Unsubscribe Copyright 2024 | Privacy Policy731 Lexington Avenue, New York, NY 10022    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/jtttxzqatjruei9qsqrv.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 15:00:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>For you: Today’s top stories</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/jtttxzqatjruei9qsqrv.html</link>
        <description>

              Context changes everything.                  View in browser Please do not reply to this message; it was sent from an unmonitored email address. If you received this message in error, please contact us. Contact Us | Advertise | Unsubscribe Copyright 2024 | Privacy Policy731 Lexington Avenue, New York, NY 10022    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/jtttxzqatjruei9qsqrv.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 15:00:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Business of Space: European independence</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/4lty0bugijd2b89pshab.html</link>
        <description>Business of Space  

      Greetings from Princeton, New Jersey. It wasn’t that long ago that European companies were major players in the space industry. Now, the EU         View in browser                                         Greetings from Princeton, New Jersey. It wasn’t that long ago that European companies were major players in the space industry. Now, the EU is trying to regain some of that luster by funding a satellite network that can compete with Elon Musk’s Starlink. But first ...Three things you need to know today:• SpaceX workers can borrow against their shares as value soars.• Canon-backed Japanese startup suffers another rocket failure.• Virgin Galactic looks to Italy as base for space tourism flights.            European satellite network finally gets the green light            There’s no love lost between some European Union officials and Elon Musk.Last December European regulators launched an investigation of his social media platform X’s handling of content, and in October he called the outgoing vice-president of the European Commission, Vera Jourova, “the epitome of banal, bureaucratic evil.”Brussels on Dec. 16 made another move to counter the billionaire’s influence by signing contracts with a consortium of European companies to begin work on an alternative to Starlink, Musk’s network of low-Earth orbit (LEO) internet satellites.  A team of people at the IRIS2 ceremony on Dec. 16. Source: European Space Agency The Commission first announced IRIS2 in November 2022, declaring that service would begin in 2024 and would “constitute a new space-based pillar for a digital, resilient and safer Europe.”The Europeans haven’t met that target, with no IRIS2 satellites in orbit, but the EU isn’t giving up and this week signed contracts with a consortium of Luxembourg-based SES, France’s Eutelsat and Spain’s Hispasat.“It's a really important milestone,” SES Chief Executive Officer Adel Al-Saleh said in an interview just before the signing. “I give a lot of credit to the Commission for really persevering because it’s complicated to get something like that. You know, the US has one government [but] you're dealing with multiple member states here to create a program like this.”Starlink, SpaceX’s network of more than 6,000 satellites, has a big head start over IRIS2 thanks to the easier access to capital and generous government support in the US, according to Al-Saleh.  Adel Al-Saleh Photographer: Andreas Rentz/Getty Images Not only does the US government “create the regulatory framework and the access to capital is attractive, they actually start using the technology,” he said. “And they give big contracts in order for these companies to be able to showcase what they can do.”Excuses aside, IRIS2 is Europe’s effort to recover some of its space luster, with local startups such as the Exploration Company getting help in developing products that SpaceX has been flying for years.The EU plans on investing €6 billion in IRIS2, but that’s still smaller than SpaceX contracts awarded by NASA, the Pentagon and others. Operating in the US is also simpler. “If you have a broadband internet service like Starlink, you can sell it across all 50 states and just deal with the FCC and other federal agencies,” said Micah Walter-Range, partner and co-founder of space consulting firm Caelus Partners. “If you’re trying to do something like that in Europe, it’s more complicated and you have to think about languages. It is a challenge.”IRIS2 won’t be a viable alternative to Starlink for years, but the short-term picture isn’t all grim for SES. For instance, ING analysts in a report published Dec. 6 point out that for all the hype, Starlink is straining to meet demand. Starlink is sold out in London, they wrote, which creates an opening for SES’s existing service from satellites that are in medium-Earth orbit.That “shows that the LEO-model has limitations, as customers have to share capacity,” according to ING. “This could bring some further confidence to SES’s MEO-model, which offers more capacity.”The IRIS2 satellites will go to space aboard Europe’s long-delayed Ariane 6, which had its debut in July but isn’t scheduled to fly again until at least mid-February. For its more recent launch, a pair of MEO satellites on Dec. 17, SES went with a more reliable option: SpaceX’s Falcon 9. — Bruce Einhorn and Gian Volpicelli                                      More services from Apple’s satellite partner              In a scoop by our colleague Mark Gurman, Bloomberg reported on Dec. 10 that some Apple smartwatch users will be able to send text messages next year using satellites operated by partner Globalstar.Still, at Globalstar’s investor day in Manhattan two days after Bloomberg broke the smartwatch news, presentations by CEO Paul Jacobs and other executives avoided nearly any mention of the name Apple. With the Cupertino-based giant extremely sensitive about its brand, Globalstar referred demurely to the updated services agreement with its “wholesale customer.”    An Ultra 2 smartwatch at an Apple store in Seoul Photographer: SeongJoon Cho/Bloomberg The latest move by Apple builds on services with Globalstar dating to 2022, when the companies first enabled SOS texting via satellite. Earlier this year, iPhone users got an upgrade with non-emergency texting, too.Last month, Globalstar’s shares soared following the announcement of an agreement to provide Apple with expanded services via a new satellite constellation. In the deal, worth $1.5 billion, Apple is to buy a 20% stake in the Covington, Louisiana-based company.Asked about more products or deals with Apple, Jacobs said he couldn’t discuss any plans. However, he added, “there are things underway that we aren't quite ready to announce yet.”Globalstar competitors in the nascent direct-to-device business have agreements with mobile network operators, like Starlink’s alliance with T-Mobile or AST SpaceMobile’s deals with AT&T and Verizon.  Paul Jacobs Photographer: David Paul Morris/Bloomberg However, Jacobs said in an interview that Globalstar’s deal with a device maker gives the company an advantage: For a phone maker, satellite connectivity is another feature that might make a consumer more willing to upgrade to a new device, while service providers will need to allocate valuable mobile spectrum – and face pressure to generate revenue to make such services worthwhile.There’s no evidence that consumers will want to stream huge amounts of data via satellite — what Jacobs called “Netflix in the mountains” — to support these large constellations. “That’s a field of dreams,” he said. — Bruce Einhorn and Sana Pashankar            Amazon’s Kuiper deadline              After President-elect Donald Trump last week said he would be meeting with Jeff Bezos, I spoke with Bloomberg Television’s Tim Stenovec about Amazon’s delays in launching its Project Kuiper satellites. The company faces a mid-2026 deadline to have more than 1,600 of Kuiper’s satellites operating and will likely need the incoming administration to grant a waiver. — Bruce Einhorn            Astroscale’s close encounter            Tokyo-based Astroscale, a specialist in tackling space junk, announced on Dec. 11 that its Adras-J spacecraft had gotten as close as about 15 meters (49 feet) to an abandoned Japanese rocket. That’s an impressive accomplishment for a company that eventually wants to be able to reach out and grab pieces of space junk.  Two days after disclosing the Adras-J flyby, the company said it lost about ¥12.9 billion ($83.8 million) in the half year ended Oct. 31, more than four times wider than its year-earlier loss, on revenue of ¥725 million.  Astroscale forecast a full-year net loss of ¥18.5 billion. Astroscale had an initial public offering in early June. The shares popped on the first day but since then they’re down more than 40%.            What we’re reading            NASA’s stuck astronauts face more time in space with return delayed until at least late March, the Associated Press reported. Chinese astronauts break world record with nine-hour spacewalk: South China Morning Post. Elon Musk and SpaceX have failed to comply with US federal reporting protocols aimed at protecting state, according to the New York Times.Power failed at SpaceX mission control before a September spacewalk by NASA nominee, Reuters reported. The Brazilian space industry got a boost in a win for embattled President Lula, Bloomberg reported.             In our orbit            Dec. 19: Two Russian cosmonauts at the International Space Station are scheduled to walk in space for six hours and forty minutes. Dec. 20: Rocket Lab to launch Earth observation satellite for Synspective, a Japanese company that has booked 16 such missions.            Talk to us            Please send us ideas, tips and questions to spacetips@bloomberg.net. As always, you can reach Bloomberg’s global business of space Team Leader, Eric Johnson, at ejohnson453@bloomberg.net (or via Signal). If you don’t receive this newsletter, you should sign up here.Last week’s newsletter incorrectly identified the planned month of Intuitive Machines’ Nova-C launch. The mission is slated for this coming February.              More from Bloomberg    Tech Daily for exclusive reporting and analysis on tech and AI Work Shift for exclusive insight and data on the future of work Business of Sports for the context you need on the collision of power, money and sports CityLab Daily for today's top stories, ideas and solutions, from cities around the world Explore all Bloomberg newsletters at Bloomberg.com.           Follow Us                                            Like getting this newsletter?  Subscribe to Bloomberg.com for unlimited access to trusted, data-driven journalism and subscriber-only insights. Before it's here, it's on the Bloomberg Terminal. Find out more about how the Terminal delivers information and analysis that financial professionals can't find anywhere else.  Learn more. Want to sponsor this newsletter?  Get in touch here.              You received this message because you are subscribed to Bloomberg's Business of Space newsletter. If a friend forwarded you this message, sign up here to get it in your inbox.       Unsubscribe  Bloomberg.com  Contact Us   Bloomberg L.P.731 Lexington Avenue,New York, NY 10022                                    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/4lty0bugijd2b89pshab.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 15:10:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Business of Space: European independence</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/4lty0bugijd2b89pshab.html</link>
        <description>Business of Space  

      Greetings from Princeton, New Jersey. It wasn’t that long ago that European companies were major players in the space industry. Now, the EU         View in browser                                         Greetings from Princeton, New Jersey. It wasn’t that long ago that European companies were major players in the space industry. Now, the EU is trying to regain some of that luster by funding a satellite network that can compete with Elon Musk’s Starlink. But first ...Three things you need to know today:• SpaceX workers can borrow against their shares as value soars.• Canon-backed Japanese startup suffers another rocket failure.• Virgin Galactic looks to Italy as base for space tourism flights.            European satellite network finally gets the green light            There’s no love lost between some European Union officials and Elon Musk.Last December European regulators launched an investigation of his social media platform X’s handling of content, and in October he called the outgoing vice-president of the European Commission, Vera Jourova, “the epitome of banal, bureaucratic evil.”Brussels on Dec. 16 made another move to counter the billionaire’s influence by signing contracts with a consortium of European companies to begin work on an alternative to Starlink, Musk’s network of low-Earth orbit (LEO) internet satellites.  A team of people at the IRIS2 ceremony on Dec. 16. Source: European Space Agency The Commission first announced IRIS2 in November 2022, declaring that service would begin in 2024 and would “constitute a new space-based pillar for a digital, resilient and safer Europe.”The Europeans haven’t met that target, with no IRIS2 satellites in orbit, but the EU isn’t giving up and this week signed contracts with a consortium of Luxembourg-based SES, France’s Eutelsat and Spain’s Hispasat.“It&#39;s a really important milestone,” SES Chief Executive Officer Adel Al-Saleh said in an interview just before the signing. “I give a lot of credit to the Commission for really persevering because it’s complicated to get something like that. You know, the US has one government [but] you&#39;re dealing with multiple member states here to create a program like this.”Starlink, SpaceX’s network of more than 6,000 satellites, has a big head start over IRIS2 thanks to the easier access to capital and generous government support in the US, according to Al-Saleh.  Adel Al-Saleh Photographer: Andreas Rentz/Getty Images Not only does the US government “create the regulatory framework and the access to capital is attractive, they actually start using the technology,” he said. “And they give big contracts in order for these companies to be able to showcase what they can do.”Excuses aside, IRIS2 is Europe’s effort to recover some of its space luster, with local startups such as the Exploration Company getting help in developing products that SpaceX has been flying for years.The EU plans on investing €6 billion in IRIS2, but that’s still smaller than SpaceX contracts awarded by NASA, the Pentagon and others. Operating in the US is also simpler. “If you have a broadband internet service like Starlink, you can sell it across all 50 states and just deal with the FCC and other federal agencies,” said Micah Walter-Range, partner and co-founder of space consulting firm Caelus Partners. “If you’re trying to do something like that in Europe, it’s more complicated and you have to think about languages. It is a challenge.”IRIS2 won’t be a viable alternative to Starlink for years, but the short-term picture isn’t all grim for SES. For instance, ING analysts in a report published Dec. 6 point out that for all the hype, Starlink is straining to meet demand. Starlink is sold out in London, they wrote, which creates an opening for SES’s existing service from satellites that are in medium-Earth orbit.That “shows that the LEO-model has limitations, as customers have to share capacity,” according to ING. “This could bring some further confidence to SES’s MEO-model, which offers more capacity.”The IRIS2 satellites will go to space aboard Europe’s long-delayed Ariane 6, which had its debut in July but isn’t scheduled to fly again until at least mid-February. For its more recent launch, a pair of MEO satellites on Dec. 17, SES went with a more reliable option: SpaceX’s Falcon 9. — Bruce Einhorn and Gian Volpicelli                                      More services from Apple’s satellite partner              In a scoop by our colleague Mark Gurman, Bloomberg reported on Dec. 10 that some Apple smartwatch users will be able to send text messages next year using satellites operated by partner Globalstar.Still, at Globalstar’s investor day in Manhattan two days after Bloomberg broke the smartwatch news, presentations by CEO Paul Jacobs and other executives avoided nearly any mention of the name Apple. With the Cupertino-based giant extremely sensitive about its brand, Globalstar referred demurely to the updated services agreement with its “wholesale customer.”    An Ultra 2 smartwatch at an Apple store in Seoul Photographer: SeongJoon Cho/Bloomberg The latest move by Apple builds on services with Globalstar dating to 2022, when the companies first enabled SOS texting via satellite. Earlier this year, iPhone users got an upgrade with non-emergency texting, too.Last month, Globalstar’s shares soared following the announcement of an agreement to provide Apple with expanded services via a new satellite constellation. In the deal, worth $1.5 billion, Apple is to buy a 20% stake in the Covington, Louisiana-based company.Asked about more products or deals with Apple, Jacobs said he couldn’t discuss any plans. However, he added, “there are things underway that we aren&#39;t quite ready to announce yet.”Globalstar competitors in the nascent direct-to-device business have agreements with mobile network operators, like Starlink’s alliance with T-Mobile or AST SpaceMobile’s deals with AT&amp;T and Verizon.  Paul Jacobs Photographer: David Paul Morris/Bloomberg However, Jacobs said in an interview that Globalstar’s deal with a device maker gives the company an advantage: For a phone maker, satellite connectivity is another feature that might make a consumer more willing to upgrade to a new device, while service providers will need to allocate valuable mobile spectrum – and face pressure to generate revenue to make such services worthwhile.There’s no evidence that consumers will want to stream huge amounts of data via satellite — what Jacobs called “Netflix in the mountains” — to support these large constellations. “That’s a field of dreams,” he said. — Bruce Einhorn and Sana Pashankar            Amazon’s Kuiper deadline              After President-elect Donald Trump last week said he would be meeting with Jeff Bezos, I spoke with Bloomberg Television’s Tim Stenovec about Amazon’s delays in launching its Project Kuiper satellites. The company faces a mid-2026 deadline to have more than 1,600 of Kuiper’s satellites operating and will likely need the incoming administration to grant a waiver. — Bruce Einhorn            Astroscale’s close encounter            Tokyo-based Astroscale, a specialist in tackling space junk, announced on Dec. 11 that its Adras-J spacecraft had gotten as close as about 15 meters (49 feet) to an abandoned Japanese rocket. That’s an impressive accomplishment for a company that eventually wants to be able to reach out and grab pieces of space junk.  Two days after disclosing the Adras-J flyby, the company said it lost about ¥12.9 billion ($83.8 million) in the half year ended Oct. 31, more than four times wider than its year-earlier loss, on revenue of ¥725 million.  Astroscale forecast a full-year net loss of ¥18.5 billion. Astroscale had an initial public offering in early June. The shares popped on the first day but since then they’re down more than 40%.            What we’re reading            NASA’s stuck astronauts face more time in space with return delayed until at least late March, the Associated Press reported. Chinese astronauts break world record with nine-hour spacewalk: South China Morning Post. Elon Musk and SpaceX have failed to comply with US federal reporting protocols aimed at protecting state, according to the New York Times.Power failed at SpaceX mission control before a September spacewalk by NASA nominee, Reuters reported. The Brazilian space industry got a boost in a win for embattled President Lula, Bloomberg reported.             In our orbit            Dec. 19: Two Russian cosmonauts at the International Space Station are scheduled to walk in space for six hours and forty minutes. Dec. 20: Rocket Lab to launch Earth observation satellite for Synspective, a Japanese company that has booked 16 such missions.            Talk to us            Please send us ideas, tips and questions to spacetips@bloomberg.net. As always, you can reach Bloomberg’s global business of space Team Leader, Eric Johnson, at ejohnson453@bloomberg.net (or via Signal). If you don’t receive this newsletter, you should sign up here.Last week’s newsletter incorrectly identified the planned month of Intuitive Machines’ Nova-C launch. The mission is slated for this coming February.              More from Bloomberg    Tech Daily for exclusive reporting and analysis on tech and AI Work Shift for exclusive insight and data on the future of work Business of Sports for the context you need on the collision of power, money and sports CityLab Daily for today&#39;s top stories, ideas and solutions, from cities around the world Explore all Bloomberg newsletters at Bloomberg.com.           Follow Us                                            Like getting this newsletter?  Subscribe to Bloomberg.com for unlimited access to trusted, data-driven journalism and subscriber-only insights. Before it&#39;s here, it&#39;s on the Bloomberg Terminal. Find out more about how the Terminal delivers information and analysis that financial professionals can&#39;t find anywhere else.  Learn more. Want to sponsor this newsletter?  Get in touch here.              You received this message because you are subscribed to Bloomberg&#39;s Business of Space newsletter. If a friend forwarded you this message, sign up here to get it in your inbox.       Unsubscribe  Bloomberg.com  Contact Us   Bloomberg L.P.731 Lexington Avenue,New York, NY 10022                                    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/4lty0bugijd2b89pshab.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 15:10:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>'Tis the season to save 50% on a full year.</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/96eomjoj8ud6zzonvb4q.html</link>
        <description>

Make the holidays magical with our special offer.  Gift yourself a year of global news and the context to understand it for just $299 $149/first year. Subscribe and save   Your subscription will give you unlimited access to: Bloomberg.com & the Bloomberg app. Live radio, podcasts and audio articles.  Expert analysis with Bloomberg TV and streaming. Subscriber-only content and newsletters.  Subscribe and save           Context changes everything.                  View in browser Pricing may vary based on applicable currency. Please do not reply to this message; it was sent from an unmonitored email address. If you received this message in error, please contact us. Contact Us | Advertise | Unsubscribe Copyright 2024 | Privacy Policy731 Lexington Avenue, New York, NY 10022    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/96eomjoj8ud6zzonvb4q.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:01:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>'Tis the season to save 50% on a full year.</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/96eomjoj8ud6zzonvb4q.html</link>
        <description>

Make the holidays magical with our special offer.  Gift yourself a year of global news and the context to understand it for just $299 $149/first year. Subscribe and save   Your subscription will give you unlimited access to: Bloomberg.com &amp; the Bloomberg app. Live radio, podcasts and audio articles.  Expert analysis with Bloomberg TV and streaming. Subscriber-only content and newsletters.  Subscribe and save           Context changes everything.                  View in browser Pricing may vary based on applicable currency. Please do not reply to this message; it was sent from an unmonitored email address. If you received this message in error, please contact us. Contact Us | Advertise | Unsubscribe Copyright 2024 | Privacy Policy731 Lexington Avenue, New York, NY 10022    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/96eomjoj8ud6zzonvb4q.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:01:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Your access has expired.</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/427fitaexfahdljr6881.html</link>
        <description>

Unlock our best offer to keep access.Subscribe today and take $170 off Business of Space is now exclusively for Bloomberg.com subscribers and your free access has ended. You will no longer receive the weekly Business of Space in your inbox. As a loyal reader, we're offering you the final chance to redeem our lowest rate of $299 $129 for your first year. By subscribing, you’ll unlock 15+ more subscriber-only newsletters, plus unlimited access to Bloomberg.com and the Bloomberg app.  Subscribe and save           Context changes everything.                  View in browser Pricing may vary based on applicable currency. Please do not reply to this message; it was sent from an unmonitored email address. If you received this message in error, please contact us. Contact Us | Advertise | Unsubscribe Copyright 2024 | Privacy Policy731 Lexington Avenue, New York, NY 10022    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/427fitaexfahdljr6881.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:00:34 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Your access has expired.</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/427fitaexfahdljr6881.html</link>
        <description>

Unlock our best offer to keep access.Subscribe today and take $170 off Business of Space is now exclusively for Bloomberg.com subscribers and your free access has ended. You will no longer receive the weekly Business of Space in your inbox. As a loyal reader, we&#39;re offering you the final chance to redeem our lowest rate of $299 $129 for your first year. By subscribing, you’ll unlock 15+ more subscriber-only newsletters, plus unlimited access to Bloomberg.com and the Bloomberg app.  Subscribe and save           Context changes everything.                  View in browser Pricing may vary based on applicable currency. Please do not reply to this message; it was sent from an unmonitored email address. If you received this message in error, please contact us. Contact Us | Advertise | Unsubscribe Copyright 2024 | Privacy Policy731 Lexington Avenue, New York, NY 10022    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/427fitaexfahdljr6881.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:00:34 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Business of Space: Fresh Artemis questions</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/ef5mr9mf58iimu7zt653.html</link>
        <description>Business of Space  

      Howdy Earthlings, it’s Loren Grush in Austin. It’s been a wild couple of weeks for news, and space is no exception. Last week, we got a new         View in browser                               Business of Space is exclusively for Bloomberg.com subscribers. As a loyal reader, you’re receiving a complimentary trial. If you’d like to continue receiving Business of Space, and gain unlimited digital access to all of Bloomberg.com, we invite you to subscribe now at the special rate of $129 for your first year (usually $299).       Learn more                  Howdy Earthlings, it’s Loren Grush in Austin. It’s been a wild couple of weeks for news, and space is no exception. Last week, we got a new NASA administrator pick and a major Artemis delay, two big events that are intricately entangled. But before we get to that ...Three things you need to know today:• SpaceX is worth a staggering $350 billion. • Rocket Lab's CEO joins the billionaire's club.• SpaceX lands Starshield contract in Ukraine.            Under pressure            The space world is still absorbing the stunning news of President-elect Donald Trump’s pick for NASA administrator: billionaire and two-time SpaceX flier Jared Isaacman. There hasn’t been a pick quite like him and he comes to the agency armed with clear opinions about SpaceX, NASA and the industry.His nomination also occurred at an interesting time. Less than 24 hours after the announcement, NASA unveiled yet another delay for its multibillion-dollar Artemis program to send people back to the moon. Isaacman has been a vocal critic of parts of Artemis. And now, given the choices that NASA announced on Thursday, I wonder if politics played a role in how the agency is moving forward with its moonshot program.  Jared Isaacman Photographer: Kelly Sullivan/Getty Images A big driver of the recent Artemis delay is the Lockheed-built Orion spacecraft, which the Artemis II astronauts will fly in around the moon.During the uncrewed dress rehearsal mission in late 2022, chunks of Orion’s heat shield (critical for protecting astronauts during return to Earth) came off when the capsule plunged through the planet’s atmosphere.That’s caused months of headaches for NASA engineers as they’ve tried to figure out whether to keep the heat shield they’ve got or redesign it altogether.We learned Thursday the plan: NASA’s keeping the heat shield. Mission managers blamed the heat shield loss on the trajectory Orion took through the atmosphere, which caused more heating than expected. So the plan is to change the capsule’s path to lessen that heating.Already, this decision has sparked controversy. For one, NASA hasn’t exactly been transparent about how it made its decision. The agency convened an independent review team to figure out the source of the heat shield issues, but hasn’t released the team’s findings. Also NASA didn’t explain well this new trajectory Orion will be taking during the press conference, with the agency instead offering jargony details that sounded more like Na’vi than English.Meanwhile, former astronaut Charles Camarda claimed on LinkedIn that he knew a few engineers at NASA who disagreed with the decision the agency ultimately picked, insinuating that managers were ignoring critical safety concerns from employees. A NASA spokesperson didn’t immediately respond to a request for comment.However, a source I spoke to at NASA reminded me the agency has a robust process for dissent, informed in part by the Space Shuttle accidents. If someone disagrees with a safety decision, he or she can escalate concerns up the managerial chain of command, all the way to the administrator. It doesn’t appear this process was blocked for anyone, the person said.Additionally, NASA needs to go through rigorous testing and qualification to determine whether the heat shield is safe to carry astronauts. That process could ultimately determine the heat shield isn’t safe, and the agency may then redesign the whole thing anyway. But what I do find a bit suspect is the timeline. NASA admitted during the presser that redesigning the heat shield would have resulted in a schedule delay of a year or more. Keeping the heat shield still came with a delay, but only seven months. NASA safety advisors are always harping on something called “schedule pressure.” It’s a term that’s often invoked as something to avoid: Don’t let an ambitious deadline sway your decision making and persuade you to cut corners.But is it possible NASA managers felt pressure to pick the option with the least bad delay at a time when new leadership was about to come into the agency? Artemis already has a big target on its back, especially from people like Isaacman, for being behind schedule and over budget. Perhaps managers thought delivering only a few months of delays to Isaacman would help prevent him from completely dismantling the program. —Loren Grush                                      Lunar lander double feature            American startup Firefly Aerospace and Japanese firm Ispace are racing to get their robotic lunar landers to the moon — literally. Both spacecraft will launch aboard the same Falcon 9 rocket in mid-January, setting off a sprint to the moon in real time, according to people familiar with the launch manifest.  A rendering of Firefly Aerospace’s Blue Ghost lunar lander. Source: Firefly Aerospace Firefly’s Blue Ghost lander will embark on its first mission to investigate the heat flow and magnetic fields of the moon. Ispace’s Resilience will make the Tokyo-based company’s second landing attempt after an initial version of the vehicle crashed into the lunar surface in April 2023. If successful, Resilience will collect samples of lunar soil and transfer them to NASA for the Artemis program. It’s likely Firefly’s lander will reach the moon first if all goes as planned. Blue Ghost will travel for about 45 days before landing on the Mare Crisium, a large basin on the near side of the moon, according to Firefly.Resilience will follow a longer trajectory, landing four to five months after its launch date, Ryo Ujiie, chief technology officer of Ispace, told reporters in September. Firefly and Ispace aren’t the only ones trying to get to the moon in the coming weeks. Houston-based Intuitive Machines, which in February became the first company to land intact on the lunar surface, is also planning to launch its Nova-C lander in January on a Falcon 9.  — Loren Grush and Sana Pashankar            European liftoff              Europe’s Vega-C rocket successfully launched into orbit last Thursday, delivering a win for the continent’s struggling space industry. It was the first time the Vega-C rocket launched since a failure in December 2022 due to a nozzle issue in its motor, according to the European Space Agency. The updated vehicle, with an improved nozzle and motor, blasted off from Europe’s spaceport in French Guiana around 6:20 p.m. local time, carrying a Copernicus Sentinel-1C satellite.The satellite successfully separated from the launcher around two hours after launch.            SpaceX soars            SpaceX and its investors agreed to purchase as much as $1.25 billion of insider shares in a deal that  valued the company at about $350 billion, according to an internal email seen by Bloomberg.The valuation confirms SpaceX as the world’s most valuable private startup, with a staggering market cap that rivals even some of the biggest public companies. The price per share of the company is $185, up from the $112 set in a prior valuation less than three months ago.   Musk’s businesses have seen an enormous boost since the US election, with investors seeking to capitalize on his deepening ties to President-elect Donald Trump. Musk’s own wealth has soared to about $384 billion, according to the Bloomberg Billionaires Index.  — Sana Pashankar            What we’re reading            Moscow is discreetly developing a space-based nuclear weapon, according to US officials, the New York Times reported.Trive Capital is exploring options, including a sale or an IPO, for Karman Space & Defense, Bloomberg News reported. Iran launched a rocket with the heaviest payload ever, Fox News reported.             In our orbit            Dec. 10-12: SpacePower conference takes place in Orlando, Florida, featuring a fireside chat with Jared Isaacman. Dec. 12: SpaceX Cargo craft is set to undock from the International Space Station at 11:05 a.m. New York time. Dec. 13: Japanese startup Space One will launch its second Kairos rocket from western Japan after a failure in March.             Talk to us            Please send us ideas, tips and questions to spacetips@bloomberg.net. As always, you can reach Bloomberg’s global business of space Team Leader, Eric Johnson, at ejohnson453@bloomberg.net (or via Signal). If you don’t receive this newsletter, you should sign up here.              More from Bloomberg    Tech Daily for exclusive reporting and analysis on tech and AI Work Shift for exclusive insight and data on the future of work Business of Sports for the context you need on the collision of power, money and sports CityLab Daily for today's top stories, ideas and solutions, from cities around the world Explore all Bloomberg newsletters at Bloomberg.com.           Follow Us                                            Like getting this newsletter?  Subscribe to Bloomberg.com for unlimited access to trusted, data-driven journalism and subscriber-only insights. Before it's here, it's on the Bloomberg Terminal. Find out more about how the Terminal delivers information and analysis that financial professionals can't find anywhere else.  Learn more. Want to sponsor this newsletter?  Get in touch here.              You received this message because you are subscribed to Bloomberg's Business of Space newsletter. If a friend forwarded you this message, sign up here to get it in your inbox.       Unsubscribe  Bloomberg.com  Contact Us   Bloomberg L.P.731 Lexington Avenue,New York, NY 10022                                    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/ef5mr9mf58iimu7zt653.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 15:35:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Business of Space: Fresh Artemis questions</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/ef5mr9mf58iimu7zt653.html</link>
        <description>Business of Space  

      Howdy Earthlings, it’s Loren Grush in Austin. It’s been a wild couple of weeks for news, and space is no exception. Last week, we got a new         View in browser                               Business of Space is exclusively for Bloomberg.com subscribers. As a loyal reader, you’re receiving a complimentary trial. If you’d like to continue receiving Business of Space, and gain unlimited digital access to all of Bloomberg.com, we invite you to subscribe now at the special rate of $129 for your first year (usually $299).       Learn more                  Howdy Earthlings, it’s Loren Grush in Austin. It’s been a wild couple of weeks for news, and space is no exception. Last week, we got a new NASA administrator pick and a major Artemis delay, two big events that are intricately entangled. But before we get to that ...Three things you need to know today:• SpaceX is worth a staggering $350 billion. • Rocket Lab&#39;s CEO joins the billionaire&#39;s club.• SpaceX lands Starshield contract in Ukraine.            Under pressure            The space world is still absorbing the stunning news of President-elect Donald Trump’s pick for NASA administrator: billionaire and two-time SpaceX flier Jared Isaacman. There hasn’t been a pick quite like him and he comes to the agency armed with clear opinions about SpaceX, NASA and the industry.His nomination also occurred at an interesting time. Less than 24 hours after the announcement, NASA unveiled yet another delay for its multibillion-dollar Artemis program to send people back to the moon. Isaacman has been a vocal critic of parts of Artemis. And now, given the choices that NASA announced on Thursday, I wonder if politics played a role in how the agency is moving forward with its moonshot program.  Jared Isaacman Photographer: Kelly Sullivan/Getty Images A big driver of the recent Artemis delay is the Lockheed-built Orion spacecraft, which the Artemis II astronauts will fly in around the moon.During the uncrewed dress rehearsal mission in late 2022, chunks of Orion’s heat shield (critical for protecting astronauts during return to Earth) came off when the capsule plunged through the planet’s atmosphere.That’s caused months of headaches for NASA engineers as they’ve tried to figure out whether to keep the heat shield they’ve got or redesign it altogether.We learned Thursday the plan: NASA’s keeping the heat shield. Mission managers blamed the heat shield loss on the trajectory Orion took through the atmosphere, which caused more heating than expected. So the plan is to change the capsule’s path to lessen that heating.Already, this decision has sparked controversy. For one, NASA hasn’t exactly been transparent about how it made its decision. The agency convened an independent review team to figure out the source of the heat shield issues, but hasn’t released the team’s findings. Also NASA didn’t explain well this new trajectory Orion will be taking during the press conference, with the agency instead offering jargony details that sounded more like Na’vi than English.Meanwhile, former astronaut Charles Camarda claimed on LinkedIn that he knew a few engineers at NASA who disagreed with the decision the agency ultimately picked, insinuating that managers were ignoring critical safety concerns from employees. A NASA spokesperson didn’t immediately respond to a request for comment.However, a source I spoke to at NASA reminded me the agency has a robust process for dissent, informed in part by the Space Shuttle accidents. If someone disagrees with a safety decision, he or she can escalate concerns up the managerial chain of command, all the way to the administrator. It doesn’t appear this process was blocked for anyone, the person said.Additionally, NASA needs to go through rigorous testing and qualification to determine whether the heat shield is safe to carry astronauts. That process could ultimately determine the heat shield isn’t safe, and the agency may then redesign the whole thing anyway. But what I do find a bit suspect is the timeline. NASA admitted during the presser that redesigning the heat shield would have resulted in a schedule delay of a year or more. Keeping the heat shield still came with a delay, but only seven months. NASA safety advisors are always harping on something called “schedule pressure.” It’s a term that’s often invoked as something to avoid: Don’t let an ambitious deadline sway your decision making and persuade you to cut corners.But is it possible NASA managers felt pressure to pick the option with the least bad delay at a time when new leadership was about to come into the agency? Artemis already has a big target on its back, especially from people like Isaacman, for being behind schedule and over budget. Perhaps managers thought delivering only a few months of delays to Isaacman would help prevent him from completely dismantling the program. —Loren Grush                                      Lunar lander double feature            American startup Firefly Aerospace and Japanese firm Ispace are racing to get their robotic lunar landers to the moon — literally. Both spacecraft will launch aboard the same Falcon 9 rocket in mid-January, setting off a sprint to the moon in real time, according to people familiar with the launch manifest.  A rendering of Firefly Aerospace’s Blue Ghost lunar lander. Source: Firefly Aerospace Firefly’s Blue Ghost lander will embark on its first mission to investigate the heat flow and magnetic fields of the moon. Ispace’s Resilience will make the Tokyo-based company’s second landing attempt after an initial version of the vehicle crashed into the lunar surface in April 2023. If successful, Resilience will collect samples of lunar soil and transfer them to NASA for the Artemis program. It’s likely Firefly’s lander will reach the moon first if all goes as planned. Blue Ghost will travel for about 45 days before landing on the Mare Crisium, a large basin on the near side of the moon, according to Firefly.Resilience will follow a longer trajectory, landing four to five months after its launch date, Ryo Ujiie, chief technology officer of Ispace, told reporters in September. Firefly and Ispace aren’t the only ones trying to get to the moon in the coming weeks. Houston-based Intuitive Machines, which in February became the first company to land intact on the lunar surface, is also planning to launch its Nova-C lander in January on a Falcon 9.  — Loren Grush and Sana Pashankar            European liftoff              Europe’s Vega-C rocket successfully launched into orbit last Thursday, delivering a win for the continent’s struggling space industry. It was the first time the Vega-C rocket launched since a failure in December 2022 due to a nozzle issue in its motor, according to the European Space Agency. The updated vehicle, with an improved nozzle and motor, blasted off from Europe’s spaceport in French Guiana around 6:20 p.m. local time, carrying a Copernicus Sentinel-1C satellite.The satellite successfully separated from the launcher around two hours after launch.            SpaceX soars            SpaceX and its investors agreed to purchase as much as $1.25 billion of insider shares in a deal that  valued the company at about $350 billion, according to an internal email seen by Bloomberg.The valuation confirms SpaceX as the world’s most valuable private startup, with a staggering market cap that rivals even some of the biggest public companies. The price per share of the company is $185, up from the $112 set in a prior valuation less than three months ago.   Musk’s businesses have seen an enormous boost since the US election, with investors seeking to capitalize on his deepening ties to President-elect Donald Trump. Musk’s own wealth has soared to about $384 billion, according to the Bloomberg Billionaires Index.  — Sana Pashankar            What we’re reading            Moscow is discreetly developing a space-based nuclear weapon, according to US officials, the New York Times reported.Trive Capital is exploring options, including a sale or an IPO, for Karman Space &amp; Defense, Bloomberg News reported. Iran launched a rocket with the heaviest payload ever, Fox News reported.             In our orbit            Dec. 10-12: SpacePower conference takes place in Orlando, Florida, featuring a fireside chat with Jared Isaacman. Dec. 12: SpaceX Cargo craft is set to undock from the International Space Station at 11:05 a.m. New York time. Dec. 13: Japanese startup Space One will launch its second Kairos rocket from western Japan after a failure in March.             Talk to us            Please send us ideas, tips and questions to spacetips@bloomberg.net. As always, you can reach Bloomberg’s global business of space Team Leader, Eric Johnson, at ejohnson453@bloomberg.net (or via Signal). If you don’t receive this newsletter, you should sign up here.              More from Bloomberg    Tech Daily for exclusive reporting and analysis on tech and AI Work Shift for exclusive insight and data on the future of work Business of Sports for the context you need on the collision of power, money and sports CityLab Daily for today&#39;s top stories, ideas and solutions, from cities around the world Explore all Bloomberg newsletters at Bloomberg.com.           Follow Us                                            Like getting this newsletter?  Subscribe to Bloomberg.com for unlimited access to trusted, data-driven journalism and subscriber-only insights. Before it&#39;s here, it&#39;s on the Bloomberg Terminal. Find out more about how the Terminal delivers information and analysis that financial professionals can&#39;t find anywhere else.  Learn more. Want to sponsor this newsletter?  Get in touch here.              You received this message because you are subscribed to Bloomberg&#39;s Business of Space newsletter. If a friend forwarded you this message, sign up here to get it in your inbox.       Unsubscribe  Bloomberg.com  Contact Us   Bloomberg L.P.731 Lexington Avenue,New York, NY 10022                                    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/ef5mr9mf58iimu7zt653.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 15:35:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Business of Space: A Trump bump</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/6agkh880yimx73t1w9z1.html</link>
        <description>Business of Space  

      Greetings space aficionados, it’s Sana in New York. A second Trump administration has space investors chomping at the bit, given the preside         View in browser                               From today, Business of Space will be exclusively for Bloomberg.com subscribers. As a loyal reader, you’ll continue receiving the newsletter until December 6. If you’d like to continue receiving Business of Space after this date, and gain unlimited digital access to all of Bloomberg.com, we invite you to subscribe now at the special rate of $149 for your first year (usually $299).       Learn more                  Greetings space aficionados, it’s Sana in New York. A second Trump administration has space investors chomping at the bit, given the president-elect’s apparent love for outer worlds and his bromance with Elon Musk. We’ll get to that in a second. But first … Three things you need to know today:• SpaceX is now worth about $350 billion.• Namibia orders Starlink to cease operations.• FCC gives Starlink conditional approval for cell coverage.             Startups look to the Pentagon             The time between the US presidential election and Inauguration Day is always filled with speculation for every sector of the economy. The space industry is no exception.One thing that a packed room full of starry-eyed investors and executives at a recent Deutsche Bank space summit in Manhattan all seemed certain about: The new administration should be good for space investment.Many attendees were upbeat over existing initiatives getting further assistance from an incoming president who is a vocal fan of space — and of SpaceX founder Elon Musk.  Donald Trump views a launch of SpaceX’s Starship in Texas last month. Photographer: Brandon Bell/Getty Images There were already “megatrends in place that now maybe get extra fire,” Edison Yu, a Deutsche Bank analyst, said in an interview. “That could be the race back to the moon, it could be trying to increase the access to internet in these remote areas of the country.”Much of the optimism revolved around the defense market.President-elect Donald Trump has indicated he would create a Space National Guard and pursue defense projects such as a missile shield like Israel’s Iron Dome anti-rocket system. He’s also a supporter of Starlink, the SpaceX satellite communication system used in warzones such as Ukraine. Space companies with the potential to win Pentagon contracts should benefit, according to Mark Boggett, chief executive officer of Seraphim, a space-focused investment firm based in London. “What I think the new administration brings is more confidence that there will be more budget and spending in defense,” he said.Investors expect the new president will try (again) to speed up the process for licensing rocket launches, as well as make it easier to get approvals for new satellite systems. These efforts would likely be aided by Musk, who has feuded with the Federal Aviation Administration over licensing procedures for SpaceX and is now in charge of the new Department of Government Efficiency, created to “slash excess regulations.”It’s a safe bet the new administration will cut red tape, said Carl Sjolund, a partner at EQT who focuses on infrastructure investment. That should help many space companies, he said, though “I think the closer you are to the administration, the more likely you would benefit.” Easing regulation may also create an environment that aids dealmaking, according to Boggett. “Consolidation will happen,” he said. “It's going to be driven by US companies acquiring European capability, and I see that happening sooner rather than later.”  A Ukrainian soldier next to a Starlink system in Bakhmut. Photographer: Yasuyoshi Chiba/AFP Even with all the talk about the pro-space policies of Trump 2.0, many young companies may still struggle to make it if they solely focus on the commercial sector, according to Tony Kim, a managing director at BlackRock.While there used to be much talk about commercial demand driving the space industry, the focus is now commercial plus government and defense, he said. “The commercial panacea,” Kim said, “has not fully been realized.” — Sana Pashankar                                      China’s launch slowdown            Among the reasons Chinese rocket makers envy SpaceX, one is a simple matter of real estate. The US allows Elon Musk’s company to use Florida’s Cape Canaveral and California’s Vandenberg, coastal facilities with plenty of open water nearby to ensure mishaps don’t result in objects crashing into people or property.Beijing hasn’t been as generous.Rather than giving companies access to the premier launch site on Hainan island in the South China Sea, the government has directed them to suboptimal alternatives in the Gobi Desert or offshore.A new facility in Hainan is supposed to change that.On Nov. 30, a Chinese rocket became the first to take off from a spaceport developed by the Hainan International Commercial Aerospace Launch Co. to promote commercial missions.Old habits die hard, though.The first rocket to launch from the site was the Long March-12 from the state-owned Shanghai Academy of Spaceflight Technology. The second launch, around the end of the year, will also be a state-owned company’s rocket, according to the official Xinhua News Agency.  A Long March-12 blasts off from the Hainan launch site Nov. 30. Photographer: VCG/VCG/Getty Images We’re still waiting to hear when the commercial center will host a mission by a truly commercial company.  The Hainan debut came at an awkward moment for China’s space program. Early this year, state media confidently predicted 100 launches in 2024, a big increase from 2023, but China has only managed about 60.The clock may be ticking for many of the private-sector companies, said Bob Savage, global head of markets strategy and insights for BNY.While China’s model has been to allow a bunch of startups, the thinking now is “we’re going to merge all of you, we’re going to get economies of scale,” he said. “The government is going to anoint one.” — Bruce Einhorn            Venture capital looks beyond Earth              Katelin Holloway, founding partner of Seven Seven Six (Reddit cofounder Alexis Ohanian’s early-stage venture capital firm), discussed its investments in space companies last week with Bloomberg’s Caroline Hyde.More non-space VCs are looking at the sector, according to Holloway. “I really do think that this is the moment,” she said. “When you see a generalist start getting involved in deep tech, I think that means that there’s something more than a trend happening.” — Bruce Einhorn            European Starlink competitor tumble           Shares of SES on Dec. 2 sank to their lowest level ever after being dropped from the Stoxx Europe 600 Index. Even before the change, the year-to-date slide of the Luxembourg-based provider of satellite broadband communications services was more than 45%.   Facing a growing threat from SpaceX’s Starlink, SES plans an  acquisition of Intelsat. The deal, with an enterprise value of $5 billion, is a reasonable reaction to the secular decline in satellite video “but precludes increased shareholder returns,” Bloomberg Intelligence senior industry analyst John Davies wrote last month.Quarterly net income plunged to €4 million, down from €770 million a year earlier, SES reported on Nov. 7.  — Bruce Einhorn            What we’re reading            What a Trump cancellation of the SLS rocket would mean for space travel’s future, King’s College London Professor Yang Gao writes in the Conversation.Taiwanese and Polish space agencies signed a cooperation agreement, Taiwan’s Central News Agency reports.With new GPS contract, Raytheon has won total of nearly $4.5 billion since upgrade began in 2010, SpaceNews reported.             In our orbit            Dec. 4: Vega-C scheduled to launch in French Guiana, the European rocket’s first mission since its 2022 failure.Dec. 5: ESA’s Proba-3 mission scheduled to launch from India.Dec. 9: Quarterly earnings call for Planet Labs.             Talk to us            Please send us ideas, tips and questions to spacetips@bloomberg.net. As always, you can reach Bloomberg’s global business of space Team Leader, Eric Johnson, at ejohnson453@bloomberg.net (or via Signal). If you don’t receive this newsletter, you should sign up here.              More from Bloomberg    Tech Daily for exclusive reporting and analysis on tech and AI Work Shift for exclusive insight and data on the future of work Business of Sports for the context you need on the collision of power, money and sports CityLab Daily for today's top stories, ideas and solutions, from cities around the world Explore all Bloomberg newsletters at Bloomberg.com.           Follow Us                                            Like getting this newsletter?  Subscribe to Bloomberg.com for unlimited access to trusted, data-driven journalism and subscriber-only insights. Before it's here, it's on the Bloomberg Terminal. Find out more about how the Terminal delivers information and analysis that financial professionals can't find anywhere else.  Learn more. Want to sponsor this newsletter?  Get in touch here.              You received this message because you are subscribed to Bloomberg's Business of Space newsletter. If a friend forwarded you this message, sign up here to get it in your inbox.       Unsubscribe  Bloomberg.com  Contact Us   Bloomberg L.P.731 Lexington Avenue,New York, NY 10022                                    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/6agkh880yimx73t1w9z1.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 15:03:36 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Business of Space: A Trump bump</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/6agkh880yimx73t1w9z1.html</link>
        <description>Business of Space  

      Greetings space aficionados, it’s Sana in New York. A second Trump administration has space investors chomping at the bit, given the preside         View in browser                               From today, Business of Space will be exclusively for Bloomberg.com subscribers. As a loyal reader, you’ll continue receiving the newsletter until December 6. If you’d like to continue receiving Business of Space after this date, and gain unlimited digital access to all of Bloomberg.com, we invite you to subscribe now at the special rate of $149 for your first year (usually $299).       Learn more                  Greetings space aficionados, it’s Sana in New York. A second Trump administration has space investors chomping at the bit, given the president-elect’s apparent love for outer worlds and his bromance with Elon Musk. We’ll get to that in a second. But first … Three things you need to know today:• SpaceX is now worth about $350 billion.• Namibia orders Starlink to cease operations.• FCC gives Starlink conditional approval for cell coverage.             Startups look to the Pentagon             The time between the US presidential election and Inauguration Day is always filled with speculation for every sector of the economy. The space industry is no exception.One thing that a packed room full of starry-eyed investors and executives at a recent Deutsche Bank space summit in Manhattan all seemed certain about: The new administration should be good for space investment.Many attendees were upbeat over existing initiatives getting further assistance from an incoming president who is a vocal fan of space — and of SpaceX founder Elon Musk.  Donald Trump views a launch of SpaceX’s Starship in Texas last month. Photographer: Brandon Bell/Getty Images There were already “megatrends in place that now maybe get extra fire,” Edison Yu, a Deutsche Bank analyst, said in an interview. “That could be the race back to the moon, it could be trying to increase the access to internet in these remote areas of the country.”Much of the optimism revolved around the defense market.President-elect Donald Trump has indicated he would create a Space National Guard and pursue defense projects such as a missile shield like Israel’s Iron Dome anti-rocket system. He’s also a supporter of Starlink, the SpaceX satellite communication system used in warzones such as Ukraine. Space companies with the potential to win Pentagon contracts should benefit, according to Mark Boggett, chief executive officer of Seraphim, a space-focused investment firm based in London. “What I think the new administration brings is more confidence that there will be more budget and spending in defense,” he said.Investors expect the new president will try (again) to speed up the process for licensing rocket launches, as well as make it easier to get approvals for new satellite systems. These efforts would likely be aided by Musk, who has feuded with the Federal Aviation Administration over licensing procedures for SpaceX and is now in charge of the new Department of Government Efficiency, created to “slash excess regulations.”It’s a safe bet the new administration will cut red tape, said Carl Sjolund, a partner at EQT who focuses on infrastructure investment. That should help many space companies, he said, though “I think the closer you are to the administration, the more likely you would benefit.” Easing regulation may also create an environment that aids dealmaking, according to Boggett. “Consolidation will happen,” he said. “It&#39;s going to be driven by US companies acquiring European capability, and I see that happening sooner rather than later.”  A Ukrainian soldier next to a Starlink system in Bakhmut. Photographer: Yasuyoshi Chiba/AFP Even with all the talk about the pro-space policies of Trump 2.0, many young companies may still struggle to make it if they solely focus on the commercial sector, according to Tony Kim, a managing director at BlackRock.While there used to be much talk about commercial demand driving the space industry, the focus is now commercial plus government and defense, he said. “The commercial panacea,” Kim said, “has not fully been realized.” — Sana Pashankar                                      China’s launch slowdown            Among the reasons Chinese rocket makers envy SpaceX, one is a simple matter of real estate. The US allows Elon Musk’s company to use Florida’s Cape Canaveral and California’s Vandenberg, coastal facilities with plenty of open water nearby to ensure mishaps don’t result in objects crashing into people or property.Beijing hasn’t been as generous.Rather than giving companies access to the premier launch site on Hainan island in the South China Sea, the government has directed them to suboptimal alternatives in the Gobi Desert or offshore.A new facility in Hainan is supposed to change that.On Nov. 30, a Chinese rocket became the first to take off from a spaceport developed by the Hainan International Commercial Aerospace Launch Co. to promote commercial missions.Old habits die hard, though.The first rocket to launch from the site was the Long March-12 from the state-owned Shanghai Academy of Spaceflight Technology. The second launch, around the end of the year, will also be a state-owned company’s rocket, according to the official Xinhua News Agency.  A Long March-12 blasts off from the Hainan launch site Nov. 30. Photographer: VCG/VCG/Getty Images We’re still waiting to hear when the commercial center will host a mission by a truly commercial company.  The Hainan debut came at an awkward moment for China’s space program. Early this year, state media confidently predicted 100 launches in 2024, a big increase from 2023, but China has only managed about 60.The clock may be ticking for many of the private-sector companies, said Bob Savage, global head of markets strategy and insights for BNY.While China’s model has been to allow a bunch of startups, the thinking now is “we’re going to merge all of you, we’re going to get economies of scale,” he said. “The government is going to anoint one.” — Bruce Einhorn            Venture capital looks beyond Earth              Katelin Holloway, founding partner of Seven Seven Six (Reddit cofounder Alexis Ohanian’s early-stage venture capital firm), discussed its investments in space companies last week with Bloomberg’s Caroline Hyde.More non-space VCs are looking at the sector, according to Holloway. “I really do think that this is the moment,” she said. “When you see a generalist start getting involved in deep tech, I think that means that there’s something more than a trend happening.” — Bruce Einhorn            European Starlink competitor tumble           Shares of SES on Dec. 2 sank to their lowest level ever after being dropped from the Stoxx Europe 600 Index. Even before the change, the year-to-date slide of the Luxembourg-based provider of satellite broadband communications services was more than 45%.   Facing a growing threat from SpaceX’s Starlink, SES plans an  acquisition of Intelsat. The deal, with an enterprise value of $5 billion, is a reasonable reaction to the secular decline in satellite video “but precludes increased shareholder returns,” Bloomberg Intelligence senior industry analyst John Davies wrote last month.Quarterly net income plunged to €4 million, down from €770 million a year earlier, SES reported on Nov. 7.  — Bruce Einhorn            What we’re reading            What a Trump cancellation of the SLS rocket would mean for space travel’s future, King’s College London Professor Yang Gao writes in the Conversation.Taiwanese and Polish space agencies signed a cooperation agreement, Taiwan’s Central News Agency reports.With new GPS contract, Raytheon has won total of nearly $4.5 billion since upgrade began in 2010, SpaceNews reported.             In our orbit            Dec. 4: Vega-C scheduled to launch in French Guiana, the European rocket’s first mission since its 2022 failure.Dec. 5: ESA’s Proba-3 mission scheduled to launch from India.Dec. 9: Quarterly earnings call for Planet Labs.             Talk to us            Please send us ideas, tips and questions to spacetips@bloomberg.net. As always, you can reach Bloomberg’s global business of space Team Leader, Eric Johnson, at ejohnson453@bloomberg.net (or via Signal). If you don’t receive this newsletter, you should sign up here.              More from Bloomberg    Tech Daily for exclusive reporting and analysis on tech and AI Work Shift for exclusive insight and data on the future of work Business of Sports for the context you need on the collision of power, money and sports CityLab Daily for today&#39;s top stories, ideas and solutions, from cities around the world Explore all Bloomberg newsletters at Bloomberg.com.           Follow Us                                            Like getting this newsletter?  Subscribe to Bloomberg.com for unlimited access to trusted, data-driven journalism and subscriber-only insights. Before it&#39;s here, it&#39;s on the Bloomberg Terminal. Find out more about how the Terminal delivers information and analysis that financial professionals can&#39;t find anywhere else.  Learn more. Want to sponsor this newsletter?  Get in touch here.              You received this message because you are subscribed to Bloomberg&#39;s Business of Space newsletter. If a friend forwarded you this message, sign up here to get it in your inbox.       Unsubscribe  Bloomberg.com  Contact Us   Bloomberg L.P.731 Lexington Avenue,New York, NY 10022                                    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/6agkh880yimx73t1w9z1.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 15:03:36 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Cyber Price Drop: Get $170 Off</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/2vuzsqjesrgir8fluo1u.html</link>
        <description>

Offer ends tonight. Unlock a full year of unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for just $299 $129.  Subscribe   Your subscription will give you unlimited access to: Bloomberg.com & the Bloomberg app. Live radio, podcasts and audio articles.  Expert analysis with Bloomberg TV and streaming. Subscriber-only content and newsletters.  Subscribe           Context changes everything.                  View in browser Pricing may vary based on applicable currency. Please do not reply to this message; it was sent from an unmonitored email address. If you received this message in error, please contact us. Contact Us | Advertise | Unsubscribe Copyright 2024 | Privacy Policy731 Lexington Avenue, New York, NY 10022    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/2vuzsqjesrgir8fluo1u.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 15:00:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Cyber Price Drop: Get $170 Off</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/2vuzsqjesrgir8fluo1u.html</link>
        <description>

Offer ends tonight. Unlock a full year of unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for just $299 $129.  Subscribe   Your subscription will give you unlimited access to: Bloomberg.com &amp; the Bloomberg app. Live radio, podcasts and audio articles.  Expert analysis with Bloomberg TV and streaming. Subscriber-only content and newsletters.  Subscribe           Context changes everything.                  View in browser Pricing may vary based on applicable currency. Please do not reply to this message; it was sent from an unmonitored email address. If you received this message in error, please contact us. Contact Us | Advertise | Unsubscribe Copyright 2024 | Privacy Policy731 Lexington Avenue, New York, NY 10022    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/2vuzsqjesrgir8fluo1u.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 15:00:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Cyber Savings: Get $160 Off</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/sax5ut5p7rnegka1kspt.html</link>
        <description>

Don’t miss our best offer of the year. Unlock a full year of unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for just $299 $139.  Subscribe   Your subscription will give you unlimited access to: Bloomberg.com & the Bloomberg app. Live radio, podcasts and audio articles.  Expert analysis with Bloomberg TV and streaming. Subscriber-only content and newsletters.  Subscribe           Context changes everything.                  View in browser Pricing may vary based on applicable currency. Please do not reply to this message; it was sent from an unmonitored email address. If you received this message in error, please contact us. Contact Us | Advertise | Unsubscribe Copyright 2024 | Privacy Policy731 Lexington Avenue, New York, NY 10022    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/sax5ut5p7rnegka1kspt.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 15:00:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Cyber Savings: Get $160 Off</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/sax5ut5p7rnegka1kspt.html</link>
        <description>

Don’t miss our best offer of the year. Unlock a full year of unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for just $299 $139.  Subscribe   Your subscription will give you unlimited access to: Bloomberg.com &amp; the Bloomberg app. Live radio, podcasts and audio articles.  Expert analysis with Bloomberg TV and streaming. Subscriber-only content and newsletters.  Subscribe           Context changes everything.                  View in browser Pricing may vary based on applicable currency. Please do not reply to this message; it was sent from an unmonitored email address. If you received this message in error, please contact us. Contact Us | Advertise | Unsubscribe Copyright 2024 | Privacy Policy731 Lexington Avenue, New York, NY 10022    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/sax5ut5p7rnegka1kspt.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 15:00:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Business of Space: The year of Blue</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/warwg1i8c3bw19569pjn.html</link>
        <description>Business of Space  

      Hello from Princeton, New Jersey. The New Glenn is years behind schedule but Blue Origin is getting ready for the rocket’s first flight, giv         View in browser                                         Hello from Princeton, New Jersey. The New Glenn is years behind schedule but Blue Origin is getting ready for the rocket’s first flight, giving the Jeff Bezos-backed company a chance to narrow the gap with Elon Musk’s SpaceX in the battle of America’s space billionaires. But first…Three things you need to know today:• Musk’s wealth hits a record $348 billion.• Opinion: Rocket Lab battles SpaceX.• Bezos hits back at Musk.            New Glenn may finally be ready for its close-up            It wasn’t the best timing for Blue Origin. Just a few days after Starship, the most ambitious rocket ever built, had its sixth test launch with President-elect Donald Trump in attendance, the Jeff Bezos-founded company had a mission of its own. Unlike Starship’s test, Blue Origin didn’t push boundaries, sending six people on a New Shepard suborbital flight on Nov. 22. That flight, the ninth with humans on board for the company, lasted roughly 10 minutes and passengers experienced zero gravity for about four minutes, crew members Marc and Sharon Hagle, the husband-and-wife septuagenarians who made their second trip on a Blue Origin rocket, told me in an interview afterwards.“It takes your breath away,” Sharon Hagle said. “It is the most emotional and spiritual journey that I’ve ever experienced.”Another crew member, Emily Calandrelli, an author and TV host who works to encourage girls to pursue STEM subjects, became the 100th woman to fly to space. “It’s scary, exhilarating, confusing, and completely and utterly joyful,” she wrote on X about the experience.   Emily Calandrelli aboard the Blue Origin New Shepard on Nov. 22. Source: Blue Origin LLC Space tourism is a bit of sideshow for Blue Origin, though. New Shepard is nice for quick jaunts to space, but the company’s future really depends on its New Glenn.When will that rocket fly? Blue Origin had been targeting a launch in November after NASA scrapped a planned October flight, though with only a few days left in the month, the window is shutting. The company sent the giant, reusable rocket to its Cape Canaveral launchpad on Nov. 21, four years behind schedule. Blue Origin did not respond to a request for comment. Blue Origin isn’t the only part of the Bezos space empire counting on New Glenn to get up and running. Amazon’s Project Kuiper satellite communications network, which aims to compete with SpaceX’s Starlink, has plans for more than 25 launches with New Glenn, according to an Evercore ISI report published last month.  Like New Glenn, Kuiper is behind schedule, with the first batch of operational satellites now expected to launch in 2025.  Jeff Bezos attends a state dinner at the White House in April. Photographer: Yuri Gripas/Abaca Another customer eagerly awaiting the first launch is AST SpaceMobile, a satellite operator. Because of the New Glenn’s size, AST will be able to launch as many as eight satellites per mission, “roughly double what is possible in the Falcon 9,” Abel Avellan, chief executive officer, said on a Nov. 14 earnings call.New Glenn “is ready to launch this year,” Avellan added.Blue Origin has about five weeks to live up the prediction. —  Bruce Einhorn                                      The air up there            Things got a little smelly on the International Space Station over the weekend when a Russian Progress cargo spacecraft arrived at the orbiting lab. After the Russian cosmonauts opened the hatch to the visiting vehicle, they “noticed an unexpected odor and observed small droplets” inside the Progress, according to NASA.That prompted the cosmonauts to seal off the module attached to the capsule, to prevent the station from being contaminated.  A portion of the International Space Station's Russian segment. Source: NASA NASA said the station’s “air scrubbers and contaminant sensors” monitored the air quality of the ISS and found it to be at “normal levels.” NASA suspects the smell was “outgassing from materials inside the cargo spacecraft.”This noxious incident is the latest in a long line of issues that Russia has been experiencing with its space station hardware over the last few years. In 2022 and 2023, two docked Russian spacecraft suffered eerily similar leaks of coolant, with both vehicles spewing liquid into space. The issue forced the crew of one of the spacecraft to stay in space much longer than planned to await a rescue vehicle.But what’s more concerning has been a series of air and pressure leaks on the Russian side of the ISS that seem to be getting worse as the station gets older. Air has been steadily escaping from a tunnel inside Russia’s Zvezda module since 2019, and the leak rate hit an all-time high this year, according to a report by NASA’s Office of the Inspector General.On Nov. 13, a NASA official warned of the potential for a “catastrophic failure” if the problem got worse, though patch work by the Russians has helped to reduce the leak rate.Hopefully the air on the ISS stays clean – and inside – for the foreseeable future. — Loren Grush            Hat trick            NASA’s powerful James Webb Space Telescope showed off its chops again this week, with the release of a spectacular, new image of a galaxy 30 million light years from Earth called Messier 104 (M104) – delightfully nicknamed the Sombrero galaxy for its resemblance to the Mexican hat. Thanks to JWST’s powerful resolution, the image shows more detail in the galaxy’s clumpy outer ring of gas and dust than we’ve been able to see before.  Visible light observed by the Hubble Space Telescope’s Advanced Camera for Surveys. Source: NASA A video from NASA compares JWST’s image to others taken by space telescopes Hubble and Spitzer to really hammer home the unparalleled clarity. — Loren Grush            Rocket Lab keeps rising            Rocket Lab’s stock rose 3.4% on Monday after Peter Beck's New Zealand-founded rocket maker said it successfully completed two space missions less than 24 hours apart from launchpads in different hemispheres. The company also won a $23.9 million contract from the US Department of Commerce. Shares jumped another 5.7% Tuesday.  Rocket Lab is seen as the clearest challenger to juggernaut SpaceX in the market for orbital transportation services using rockets that are flown multiple times. The Nov. 25 “Ice AIS Baby” mission was Rocket Lab’s 14th in 2024 and 56th launch overall. The company is now second only to Elon Musk's SpaceX and China in the tempo of its launches. Rocket Lab shares are up more than 350% this year.Rocket Lab aims to take its SpaceX rivalry into a higher orbit when it brings its larger Neutron rocket to market as soon as the middle of next year. — Eric Johnson            What we’re reading            NASA warns of potential ISS failure but Russia disagrees, LiveScience reports.Neil deGrasse Tyson exchanged barbs with Elon Musk on Mars colonization, TheWrap reports.ISRO twice had to move India’s lunar orbiter to avoid collisions with US, Korean spacecraft, according to The Register.            In our orbit            Dec. 3: UN-sponsored conference on space sustainability opens in Bonn, Germany.Dec. 4: Proba-3, joint European-Indian mission, scheduled to launch from space center near Chennai.This week: The Long March-12 rocket expected to make its first flight, according to Chinese media.            Talk to us            Please send us ideas, tips and questions to spacetips@bloomberg.net. As always, you can reach Bloomberg’s global business of space editor, Eric Johnson, at ejohnson453@bloomberg.net (or via Signal). If you don’t receive this newsletter, you should sign up here.              More from Bloomberg    Tech Daily for exclusive reporting and analysis on tech and AI Work Shift for exclusive insight and data on the future of work Business of Sports for the context you need on the collision of power, money and sports CityLab Daily for today's top stories, ideas and solutions, from cities around the world Explore all Bloomberg newsletters at Bloomberg.com.           Follow Us                                            Like getting this newsletter?  Subscribe to Bloomberg.com for unlimited access to trusted, data-driven journalism and subscriber-only insights. Before it's here, it's on the Bloomberg Terminal. Find out more about how the Terminal delivers information and analysis that financial professionals can't find anywhere else.  Learn more. Want to sponsor this newsletter?  Get in touch here.              You received this message because you are subscribed to Bloomberg's Business of Space newsletter. If a friend forwarded you this message, sign up here to get it in your inbox.       Unsubscribe  Bloomberg.com  Contact Us   Bloomberg L.P.731 Lexington Avenue,New York, NY 10022                                    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/warwg1i8c3bw19569pjn.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 15:01:43 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Business of Space: The year of Blue</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/warwg1i8c3bw19569pjn.html</link>
        <description>Business of Space  

      Hello from Princeton, New Jersey. The New Glenn is years behind schedule but Blue Origin is getting ready for the rocket’s first flight, giv         View in browser                                         Hello from Princeton, New Jersey. The New Glenn is years behind schedule but Blue Origin is getting ready for the rocket’s first flight, giving the Jeff Bezos-backed company a chance to narrow the gap with Elon Musk’s SpaceX in the battle of America’s space billionaires. But first…Three things you need to know today:• Musk’s wealth hits a record $348 billion.• Opinion: Rocket Lab battles SpaceX.• Bezos hits back at Musk.            New Glenn may finally be ready for its close-up            It wasn’t the best timing for Blue Origin. Just a few days after Starship, the most ambitious rocket ever built, had its sixth test launch with President-elect Donald Trump in attendance, the Jeff Bezos-founded company had a mission of its own. Unlike Starship’s test, Blue Origin didn’t push boundaries, sending six people on a New Shepard suborbital flight on Nov. 22. That flight, the ninth with humans on board for the company, lasted roughly 10 minutes and passengers experienced zero gravity for about four minutes, crew members Marc and Sharon Hagle, the husband-and-wife septuagenarians who made their second trip on a Blue Origin rocket, told me in an interview afterwards.“It takes your breath away,” Sharon Hagle said. “It is the most emotional and spiritual journey that I’ve ever experienced.”Another crew member, Emily Calandrelli, an author and TV host who works to encourage girls to pursue STEM subjects, became the 100th woman to fly to space. “It’s scary, exhilarating, confusing, and completely and utterly joyful,” she wrote on X about the experience.   Emily Calandrelli aboard the Blue Origin New Shepard on Nov. 22. Source: Blue Origin LLC Space tourism is a bit of sideshow for Blue Origin, though. New Shepard is nice for quick jaunts to space, but the company’s future really depends on its New Glenn.When will that rocket fly? Blue Origin had been targeting a launch in November after NASA scrapped a planned October flight, though with only a few days left in the month, the window is shutting. The company sent the giant, reusable rocket to its Cape Canaveral launchpad on Nov. 21, four years behind schedule. Blue Origin did not respond to a request for comment. Blue Origin isn’t the only part of the Bezos space empire counting on New Glenn to get up and running. Amazon’s Project Kuiper satellite communications network, which aims to compete with SpaceX’s Starlink, has plans for more than 25 launches with New Glenn, according to an Evercore ISI report published last month.  Like New Glenn, Kuiper is behind schedule, with the first batch of operational satellites now expected to launch in 2025.  Jeff Bezos attends a state dinner at the White House in April. Photographer: Yuri Gripas/Abaca Another customer eagerly awaiting the first launch is AST SpaceMobile, a satellite operator. Because of the New Glenn’s size, AST will be able to launch as many as eight satellites per mission, “roughly double what is possible in the Falcon 9,” Abel Avellan, chief executive officer, said on a Nov. 14 earnings call.New Glenn “is ready to launch this year,” Avellan added.Blue Origin has about five weeks to live up the prediction. —  Bruce Einhorn                                      The air up there            Things got a little smelly on the International Space Station over the weekend when a Russian Progress cargo spacecraft arrived at the orbiting lab. After the Russian cosmonauts opened the hatch to the visiting vehicle, they “noticed an unexpected odor and observed small droplets” inside the Progress, according to NASA.That prompted the cosmonauts to seal off the module attached to the capsule, to prevent the station from being contaminated.  A portion of the International Space Station&#39;s Russian segment. Source: NASA NASA said the station’s “air scrubbers and contaminant sensors” monitored the air quality of the ISS and found it to be at “normal levels.” NASA suspects the smell was “outgassing from materials inside the cargo spacecraft.”This noxious incident is the latest in a long line of issues that Russia has been experiencing with its space station hardware over the last few years. In 2022 and 2023, two docked Russian spacecraft suffered eerily similar leaks of coolant, with both vehicles spewing liquid into space. The issue forced the crew of one of the spacecraft to stay in space much longer than planned to await a rescue vehicle.But what’s more concerning has been a series of air and pressure leaks on the Russian side of the ISS that seem to be getting worse as the station gets older. Air has been steadily escaping from a tunnel inside Russia’s Zvezda module since 2019, and the leak rate hit an all-time high this year, according to a report by NASA’s Office of the Inspector General.On Nov. 13, a NASA official warned of the potential for a “catastrophic failure” if the problem got worse, though patch work by the Russians has helped to reduce the leak rate.Hopefully the air on the ISS stays clean – and inside – for the foreseeable future. — Loren Grush            Hat trick            NASA’s powerful James Webb Space Telescope showed off its chops again this week, with the release of a spectacular, new image of a galaxy 30 million light years from Earth called Messier 104 (M104) – delightfully nicknamed the Sombrero galaxy for its resemblance to the Mexican hat. Thanks to JWST’s powerful resolution, the image shows more detail in the galaxy’s clumpy outer ring of gas and dust than we’ve been able to see before.  Visible light observed by the Hubble Space Telescope’s Advanced Camera for Surveys. Source: NASA A video from NASA compares JWST’s image to others taken by space telescopes Hubble and Spitzer to really hammer home the unparalleled clarity. — Loren Grush            Rocket Lab keeps rising            Rocket Lab’s stock rose 3.4% on Monday after Peter Beck&#39;s New Zealand-founded rocket maker said it successfully completed two space missions less than 24 hours apart from launchpads in different hemispheres. The company also won a $23.9 million contract from the US Department of Commerce. Shares jumped another 5.7% Tuesday.  Rocket Lab is seen as the clearest challenger to juggernaut SpaceX in the market for orbital transportation services using rockets that are flown multiple times. The Nov. 25 “Ice AIS Baby” mission was Rocket Lab’s 14th in 2024 and 56th launch overall. The company is now second only to Elon Musk&#39;s SpaceX and China in the tempo of its launches. Rocket Lab shares are up more than 350% this year.Rocket Lab aims to take its SpaceX rivalry into a higher orbit when it brings its larger Neutron rocket to market as soon as the middle of next year. — Eric Johnson            What we’re reading            NASA warns of potential ISS failure but Russia disagrees, LiveScience reports.Neil deGrasse Tyson exchanged barbs with Elon Musk on Mars colonization, TheWrap reports.ISRO twice had to move India’s lunar orbiter to avoid collisions with US, Korean spacecraft, according to The Register.            In our orbit            Dec. 3: UN-sponsored conference on space sustainability opens in Bonn, Germany.Dec. 4: Proba-3, joint European-Indian mission, scheduled to launch from space center near Chennai.This week: The Long March-12 rocket expected to make its first flight, according to Chinese media.            Talk to us            Please send us ideas, tips and questions to spacetips@bloomberg.net. As always, you can reach Bloomberg’s global business of space editor, Eric Johnson, at ejohnson453@bloomberg.net (or via Signal). If you don’t receive this newsletter, you should sign up here.              More from Bloomberg    Tech Daily for exclusive reporting and analysis on tech and AI Work Shift for exclusive insight and data on the future of work Business of Sports for the context you need on the collision of power, money and sports CityLab Daily for today&#39;s top stories, ideas and solutions, from cities around the world Explore all Bloomberg newsletters at Bloomberg.com.           Follow Us                                            Like getting this newsletter?  Subscribe to Bloomberg.com for unlimited access to trusted, data-driven journalism and subscriber-only insights. Before it&#39;s here, it&#39;s on the Bloomberg Terminal. Find out more about how the Terminal delivers information and analysis that financial professionals can&#39;t find anywhere else.  Learn more. Want to sponsor this newsletter?  Get in touch here.              You received this message because you are subscribed to Bloomberg&#39;s Business of Space newsletter. If a friend forwarded you this message, sign up here to get it in your inbox.       Unsubscribe  Bloomberg.com  Contact Us   Bloomberg L.P.731 Lexington Avenue,New York, NY 10022                                    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/warwg1i8c3bw19569pjn.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 15:01:43 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Our best offer of the year. Get $160 Off.</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/b0gzacj2if7hq7zk62mf.html</link>
        <description>

Early access won’t last. Celebrate Cyber by unlocking a full year of Bloomberg.com for just $299 $139.  Subscribe   Your subscription will give you unlimited access to: Bloomberg.com & the Bloomberg app. Live radio, podcasts and audio articles.  Expert analysis with Bloomberg TV and streaming. Subscriber-only content and newsletters.  Subscribe           Context changes everything.                  View in browser Pricing may vary based on applicable currency. Please do not reply to this message; it was sent from an unmonitored email address. If you received this message in error, please contact us. Contact Us | Advertise | Unsubscribe Copyright 2024 | Privacy Policy731 Lexington Avenue, New York, NY 10022    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/b0gzacj2if7hq7zk62mf.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 15:00:09 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Our best offer of the year. Get $160 Off.</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/b0gzacj2if7hq7zk62mf.html</link>
        <description>

Early access won’t last. Celebrate Cyber by unlocking a full year of Bloomberg.com for just $299 $139.  Subscribe   Your subscription will give you unlimited access to: Bloomberg.com &amp; the Bloomberg app. Live radio, podcasts and audio articles.  Expert analysis with Bloomberg TV and streaming. Subscriber-only content and newsletters.  Subscribe           Context changes everything.                  View in browser Pricing may vary based on applicable currency. Please do not reply to this message; it was sent from an unmonitored email address. If you received this message in error, please contact us. Contact Us | Advertise | Unsubscribe Copyright 2024 | Privacy Policy731 Lexington Avenue, New York, NY 10022    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/b0gzacj2if7hq7zk62mf.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 15:00:09 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Early Access Cyber Special: Take $160 Off</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/x6zpg6rhajexml0k1sor.html</link>
        <description>

Take advantage of our best offer of the year. Celebrate Cyber by unlocking a full year of Bloomberg.com for just $299 $139.  Subscribe   Your subscription will give you unlimited access to: Bloomberg.com & the Bloomberg app. Live radio, podcasts and audio articles.  Expert analysis with Bloomberg TV and streaming. Subscriber-only content and newsletters.  Subscribe           Context changes everything.                  View in browser Pricing may vary based on applicable currency. Please do not reply to this message; it was sent from an unmonitored email address. If you received this message in error, please contact us. Contact Us | Advertise | Unsubscribe Copyright 2024 | Privacy Policy731 Lexington Avenue, New York, NY 10022    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/x6zpg6rhajexml0k1sor.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:01:48 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Early Access Cyber Special: Take $160 Off</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/x6zpg6rhajexml0k1sor.html</link>
        <description>

Take advantage of our best offer of the year. Celebrate Cyber by unlocking a full year of Bloomberg.com for just $299 $139.  Subscribe   Your subscription will give you unlimited access to: Bloomberg.com &amp; the Bloomberg app. Live radio, podcasts and audio articles.  Expert analysis with Bloomberg TV and streaming. Subscriber-only content and newsletters.  Subscribe           Context changes everything.                  View in browser Pricing may vary based on applicable currency. Please do not reply to this message; it was sent from an unmonitored email address. If you received this message in error, please contact us. Contact Us | Advertise | Unsubscribe Copyright 2024 | Privacy Policy731 Lexington Avenue, New York, NY 10022    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/x6zpg6rhajexml0k1sor.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:01:48 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Your access is expiring</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/yly1wuzasptaecgw38zy.html</link>
        <description>

Take 50% off today to keep reading.Your newsletter access is expiring Business of Space is now subscriber-only and your free access is ending soon. As a loyal reader, we’re offering you an exclusive, limited-time rate of just $149 for your first year—50% off the regular of $299. By subscribing, you’ll unlock 15+ other subscriber-only newsletters, plus unlimited access to Bloomberg.com and the Bloomberg app.   Plus, you’ll also get live radio, exclusive podcasts, and audio articles, so you can stay informed and inspired wherever you go. Subscribe today and keep discovering more with Bloomberg.com. Subscribe and save           Context changes everything.                  View in browser Pricing may vary based on applicable currency. Please do not reply to this message; it was sent from an unmonitored email address. If you received this message in error, please contact us. Contact Us | Advertise | Unsubscribe Copyright 2024 | Privacy Policy731 Lexington Avenue, New York, NY 10022    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/yly1wuzasptaecgw38zy.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 21:30:09 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Your access is expiring</title>
        <link>https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/yly1wuzasptaecgw38zy.html</link>
        <description>

Take 50% off today to keep reading.Your newsletter access is expiring Business of Space is now subscriber-only and your free access is ending soon. As a loyal reader, we’re offering you an exclusive, limited-time rate of just $149 for your first year—50% off the regular of $299. By subscribing, you’ll unlock 15+ other subscriber-only newsletters, plus unlimited access to Bloomberg.com and the Bloomberg app.   Plus, you’ll also get live radio, exclusive podcasts, and audio articles, so you can stay informed and inspired wherever you go. Subscribe today and keep discovering more with Bloomberg.com. Subscribe and save           Context changes everything.                  View in browser Pricing may vary based on applicable currency. Please do not reply to this message; it was sent from an unmonitored email address. If you received this message in error, please contact us. Contact Us | Advertise | Unsubscribe Copyright 2024 | Privacy Policy731 Lexington Avenue, New York, NY 10022    




Kill the Newsletter! feed settings

</description>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://kill-the-newsletter.com/feeds/88lhiotcswouh2kqelf0/entries/yly1wuzasptaecgw38zy.html</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 21:30:09 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    </channel>
 </rss>